常用的替代速度曲线如下所示。
A commonly used alternative velocity profile looks like this.
我们加速。只要我们需要，我们以恒定速度移动
We accelerate. We move at constant velocity for as long as we need to
然后我们尽快放慢速度。
and then we slow down as quickly as we can.
像这样的轨迹的一个优点是我们可以更快地到达目的地。
An advantage of a trajectory like this is that we get to our destination much more quickly.
两条曲线下方的区域是行进的距离，两者中的区域相同
The area under the two curves is the distance travelled, and that's the same in the two
案例。只是红色曲线更加紧凑。它只需要35个时间单位
cases. It’s just that the red curve is much more compact. It only takes 35 time units
而不是50个时间单位。
instead of 50 time units.
这种运动被称为梯形轮廓。它的名字取决于它的形状
This kind of motion is referred to as a trapezoidal profile. It's named after the shape of the
速度曲线。这是一个梯形。它包括一个加速阶段，一个滑行阶段-在哪里
velocity profile. It’s a trapezoid. It comprises an acceleration phase, a coasting phase - where
我们以恒定速度移动-然后是减速阶段。在加速期间和
we move at a constant velocity - and then a deceleration phase. During acceleration and
减速时，速度是时间的线性函数。这意味着，该位置是抛物线
deceleration, the velocity is a linear function of time. Which means, that position is a parabolic
时间的功能。在滑行阶段，速度是恒定的。这意味着
function of time. During the coasting phase, the velocity is constant. That means that
位置轮廓是一条直线。所以，这种运动轮廓，梯形
the position profile is a straight line. So, this kind of motion profile, the trapezoidal
轮廓，有时也被称为具有抛物线混合的线性段。在
profile, is also sometimes referred to as a linear segment with parabolic blend. In
机器人工具箱，它是函数LSPB，它是线性段的收缩
that robotics toolbox, it's the function LSPB which is a contraction of a linear segment
与抛物线混合。
with parabolic blend.
梯形轮廓的缺点是加速度不连续
A disadvantage of the trapezoidal profile is that acceleration is not continuous and
当我们从加速阶段转换到惯性阶段和滑行到减速时，你可以看到它
you can see it when we change from acceleration phase to coasting phase and coasting to deceleration
阶段，加速阶段存在阶梯不连续性。这对某些机器人来说可能存在问题
phase, there is a step discontinuity in acceleration. This is potentially problematic for some robots
但总的来说，我们依赖于运动控制系统的带宽这一事实
but in general, we rely on the fact that the bandwidth of the motion control systems is
相对较低并且平滑了加速度的这种不连续性。
relatively low and it smooths out this discontinuity in acceleration.
让我们使用MATLAB工具来看这种类型的轨迹，我将创建一个梯形
Let's look at this type of trajectory using the MATLAB tools, I am going to create a trapezoidal
使用MATLAB函数LSPB的轨迹，它是LinearSegment的首字母缩写
trajectory using the MATLAB function LSPB which is an acronym for Linear Segment with
抛物线混合。它将以零值开始。它将完成
Parabolic Blend. It's going to start with the value of zero. It's going to finish at
一。我们将以50次步骤完成。而且，在这里我们看到了轨迹。我们可以清楚
one. We're going to do it in 50 times steps. And, here we see the trajectory. We can clearly
看到速度曲线是梯形的。我们可以看到加速阶段，常数
see that the velocity profile is trapezoidal. We can see the acceleration phase, the constant
速度阶段和减速阶段。并且，这些不同的阶段是彩色编码的
velocity phase and the deceleration phase. And, these different phases are color coded
在S与时间步骤的关系图中。我可以改变轨迹。所以，而不是从
in the plot of S versus time step. I can change the trajectory. So, instead of going from
零到一，从零到零。而且，现在的轨迹看起来像这样。所以，
zero to one, it goes from zero to minus one. And, the trajectory now looks like this. So,
那么，我可以要求S的值，从50到1的步数为0。它创造了
then, I can ask for the values of S, from zero to one in 50 times steps. And it creates
工作区代码S中有50行的向量。每行对应一个时间步。
a vector in the workspace code S which has 50 rows. Each row corresponds to a time step.
就像tpoly函数一样，我也可以询问速度和加速度
And just like the tpoly function, I can also ask for the velocity and the acceleration
反过来，我们将SD和STD放入工作空间，这里它们也在工作空间中
which in turn, we put into the workspace SD and STD and here they are also in the workspace
作为50个元素向量，每个时间步长一行。
as 50 element vectors, one row per time step.
我将回到我的第一个例子。从零到一的轨迹。我们可以看到
I'm going to return to my first example. A trajectory from zero to one. We can see that
线性段的速度略高于0.03。我们现在要做什么
the velocity of the linear segment is a little bit above 0.03. What we are going to do now
是覆盖自动选择线性段的速度。而且，我要走了
is to override the automatic choice of the velocity of the linear segment. And, I'm going
建议使用0.025的值代替。而且，在这里我们可以看到轨迹正在发生
to suggest that it use a value of 0.025 instead. And, here we can see the trajectory is being
计算。您会看到线性段现在更长并且抛物线混合
computed. You see that the linear segment now is much longer and the parabolic blends
要短得多。我建议它使用稍大的速度值
are much shorter. I am going to suggest that it uses a slightly larger value of velocity
对于线性段。而且，现在我们可以看到线性段非常短而抛物线
for the linear segment. And, now we can see linear segment's quite short and the parabolic
混合物更长。线性段速度的可行值范围是
blends are longer. The range of feasible values for the velocity of the linear segment are
实际上非常有限。并且，如果我建议值为0.02，则返回错误指示
actually quite limited. And, if I suggest a value of 0.02, it is returning an error indicating
我指定的速度太小了。计算梯形是不可能的
that the velocity that I specified is too small. It's not possible to compute a trapezoidal
具有该线性段的速度值的轮廓。
profile with that value of velocity for the linear segment.